SUMANRAJ RAMESH BANGERA



Contact details: - +918433260633 Email: - sumanrajbangera@gmail.com

A. OBJECTIVE

More than 8 Year experience in VMware, OLVM, Linux, Windows Administrator with detailed knowledge of Remote Infrastructure Management in Administering, Troubleshooting, Upgrading & Maintaining Linux/Windows Servers.

B. Profile Summary:

Significant experience on VMware, OLVM, Linux, Windows, Azure Cloud

Very good experience in troubleshooting OS, network, access and package related issues.

A team player with a good communication & analytic skill.

C. Core Competencies

Installing and troubleshooting of Linux (RHEL,SUSE,OEL) ,Windows's(2012,2016&2019).
Installing and Configuring Azure VM's servers.
Installing and configuring of ESXi Servers, vSphere Client and Vcenter Server 6,6.5&6.7
Installing and Configuring of Oracle Virtual Machine and OLVM.
Installing and Configuring Cisco UCS, HP & Dell Servers.
Handling priority incident and find the root cause of the issue to prepare the RCA
Handling quires of L2 team and providing the solution for issue.
Support MS team in migration of Onprem server to Azure cloud
Installation & upgradation of OS, Kernel & additional packages using RPM & yum
Good Troubleshooting analytic skill
Perform Security Hardening and OS Hardening.
Maintaining server security, backup, and restoration measures for unplanned outages or other OS/Application-level issues.
Replication VM's across VCenter using Veeam Application.

D. Skills

- Operating System: Windows Server 2008/2012/2016, RHEL 6 & 7 ,SUSE ,Oracle
- Cluster SAP Cluster, RHEL Cluster
- Virtualization VMware, OLVM
- Cloud Azure, AWS

E. Professional Experience

- Capgemini: Senior Consultant from April 2020 till date.
- **L&T Infotech**: System Engineer from November 2018 to April 2020.
- **Tech Mahindra Ltd**: System Engineer from November 2016 to October 2018.
- Ocwen Financial Solution Pvt Ltd.: Jr Technical System Engineer from April 2015 to Nov 2016.
- **Crystal Solution**: IT Engineer from Jan 2014 to March 2015.
- IT Source India Pvt Ltd.: DL2 Engineer from July 2012 to July 2013.

F. Professional Qualification

- ➤ Completed CCNA Course from RST Forum.
- ➤ Completed MSCS Course from IP SOLUTIONS.
- ➤ Well versed with the concepts of Networking and Information security.
- > Certified Ethical Hacker Certification Exam from EC-Council ATC (Quest institute, Mumbai)
- > Certified Training in IMS SI Training in VMware, NetAPP, ITIL.
- Certified VTSP-HCI (Hyper-Converged Infrastructure)
- ➤ Completed AWS Course from Attari Classes.
- ➤ Completed ITIL v4 certification
- ➤ Completed Az 900 Certification
- ➤ Completed Az 104 Certification

G. ACADEMIC PROFILE

QUALIFICATION (Name of Degree/ Diploma)	INSTITUTION	AFFILIATED TO	YEAR OF PASSING
B.C.A	St.Angelos Pvt.	YCMOU	May-2012
H.S.C	Balbharati College	Maharashtra Board	Feb-2009
S.S.C	John XXIII High School	Maharashtra Board	March-2007

H. DECLARATION

]	I hereby	declar	e that	all the	e inf	ormation	includ	ed l	herewith	ı is	true	to my	know	leds	ge.

Place: - Mumbai

Date: -

SUMANRAJ R.BANGERA